Biophysical Society records
Biophysical Society records
- Series II. Meetings, 1956-2002; bulk 1963-1997; 173 folders (7.25 linear feet)
  - Subseries II.A. Annual Meetings, 1956-2000; bulk 1963-1997; 164 folders (7 linear feet)
    - Programs, 1983-1986 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Programs, 2000 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Programs, 2009 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Subseries II.B. Miscellaneous Meetings and Conferences, 1961-2002; 9 folders (.25 linear feet)
    Correspondence, memos, and printed reports arranged in alphabetical order with items of the same name in order by date.
    - 7th Biophysical Discussion, Correspondence, October 23-24, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - International Biophysics Congress, Correspondence, 1961, 1965-67 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - International Biophysics Congress, Memo to Members, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - International Biophysics Congress, Stockholm, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - International Biophysics Congress, 2nd, Vienna, Austria, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - International Biophysics Congress, 10th, Vancouver, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - International Biophysics Congress, 11th, Budapest, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - International Biophysics Congress, 14th Buenos Aires, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - International Biophysics Congress, Travel Grants/Awards, 1987-93 (Box 16, Folder 9)
- Series III. Committees, 1956-2009; bulk 1980-1997; 113 folders (6.25 linear feet)
  Committee agendas, minutes, correspondence, memos, reports, directories and rosters arranged into eight Subseries by committee name.
  - Subseries III.A. Awards Committee, 1983-1997; bulk 1990-1997; 12 folders (.5 linear feet)
    Correspondence, nominating material, and ballots and voting instructions for various Society awards; arranged in alphabetical order.
    - Correspondence, 1991-92, 1994-97 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Distinguished Service Award, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Distinguished Service, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Elisabeth Roberts Cole Award, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Elisabeth Roberts Cole Award, 1991-July 1992 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Elisabeth Roberts Cole Award, Sept-Oct 1992 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Elisabeth Roberts Cole Award, Nov 1992-April 1993 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Margaret Oakley Dayhoff Memorial Award, 1983, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Margaret Oakley Dayhoff Memorial Award, 1989-90 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Margaret Oakley Dayhoff Memorial Award, 1990-94 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Young Investigator Award, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Young Investigator Award, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Subseries III.B. Educational Affairs Committee, 1959-1997; bulk 1973-1994; 13 folders (.75 linear feet)
    General correspondence, school lists, questionnaires, and correspondence related to Student Symposia, and printed material from workshops; arranged in alphabetical order.
    - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, 1962-1964 (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence, 1965-1967 (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence, 1989-90 (Jan-June) (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence, 1990 (July-Dec) (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1992-94, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Student Symposia, 1988-1991 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Student Symposia, 1992-1993, 1996-1997 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Workshops, 1984, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Workshops, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Annual Meeting March 2009 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Subseries III.C. Innovative Technology Fund Advisory Committee (ITFAC), 1956-1998; bulk 1980-1997; 5 folders (.5 linear feet)
    Correspondence, progress reports, and articles arranged in date order.
    - Correspondence, Aug-Oct 1991 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, Nov-Dec 1991 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, Jan-May 1992 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, June-Dec 1992 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Subseries III.D. Joint Steering Committee, 1991-1996; 12 folders (1 linear foot)
    Correspondence, memos, reports, agendas, and minutes arranged in date order.
    - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, Memos and Reports, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Committee Meeting, Agenda and Minutes, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, Memos and Reports, Jan-April 1993 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, Memos and Reports, May-Dec 1993 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Committee Meeting, Agenda and Minutes, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, Memos and Reports, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Committee Meeting, Agenda and Minutes, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence, Memos and Reports, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Committee Meeting, Agenda and Minutes, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, Memos and Reports, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Committee Meeting, Agenda and Minutes, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Subseries III.E. Membership Committee, 1957-1999; 17 folders (1 linear foot)
    Correspondence, dues lists, membership statistics, surveys and questionnaires, and printed directories arranged in alphabetical order.
    - Correspondence, 1958-1963 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1986-1996 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Directories, 1957,1959-1961, 1964 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Directories, 1966-1967, 1969, 1971-1972 (copy) (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Directories, 1971, 1974, 1976, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Directories, 1980, 1982, 1984/85 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Directories, 1990-93 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Directories, 1993/94, 1997-99 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Directories, 2008 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Field of Activity (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - List of Biophysicists, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Membership Analysis (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Membership Dues (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Member Lists (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Questionnaire (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Reports (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Statistics (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Survey of Unpaid Members, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Subseries III.F. Nominating Committee, 1958-1998; 17 folders (1.25 linear feet)
    Correspondence, officer nomination lists, biographical sketches of nominees (including the original forms filled out by the nominees), nomination forms, election totals, and email correspondence; arranged in date order.
    - Correspondence, 1958-1960 (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, 1961 (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 18, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence, 1966-1967, 1971, 1973-1975 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1985-1988 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, Jan-June 1991 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, July-Dec 1991 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, Jan-May 1992 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, June-Dec 1992 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, Jan-April 1993 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, May-Sept 1993 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Subseries III.G. Miscellaneous Committees, 1956-1998; 33 folders (1 linear foot)
    Correspondence, newsletters, reports, and committee lists arranged in alphabetical order.
    - Committee Handbook, June 1997 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Ad Hoc Committee, 1961 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Ad Hoc Committee, 1989-1990 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Ad Hoc Committee, 1994 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Affiliations Committee (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Biophysical Discussions (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Committee on Fellows, 1961-1962 (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - Committee on Physics Textbooks, 1962 (ad hoc) (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - Committee on Professional Opportunities for Women, 1987-88, 1990-95 (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Extracurricular Activities Committee (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - Extramural Activities Committee, 1963-65 (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - Finance Committee, 1961 (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - Future Meetings Committee (Box 19, Folder 25)
    - Information Committee (Office of Information) (Box 19, Folder 26)
    - Local Arrangements Committee, 1961 (Box 19, Folder 27)
    - International Relations Committee, 1958-60 (Box 19, Folder 28)
    - International Relations Committee, 1961-65 (Box 19, Folder 29)
    - Minority Affairs Committee, Correspondence, 1994 (Box 19, Folder 30)
    - National Medal of Science, 1963-66 (Box 19, Folder 31)
    - The Neutron Structural Biology Task Force, Jan-June 1991 (Box 19, Folder 32)
    - The Neutron Structural Biology Task Force, July 1991-Feb 1992 (Box 19, Folder 33)
    - Operations Committee, 1991-98 (Box 19, Folder 34)
    - Placement Service, 1957-1962 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Placement Service, 1963-1967 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Placement Service, Report, 1989-1990 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Placement Service, 1990-91 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Professional Grievances Advisory Committee, 1972-1973 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Public Affairs, 1992 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Public Policy Committee, Correspondence, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Public Science Policy Committee (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Publicity Committee, 1956-1963 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Scientific Communications Committee (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Standing Program Committee (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Subseries III.H. Public Affairs Committee, 2007-2009; 4 folders (.25 linear feet)
    - Annual Meeting March 2007 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Annual Meeting February 2010 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Annual Meeting March 2009 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Annual Meeting October 2009 (Box 20, Folder 15)
- Series IV. Publications, 1956-2008; 55 folders (2.5 linear feet)
  Correspondence, reports, financial statements, agendas, minutes, and copies of newsletters arranged into three Subseries by topic.
  - Subseries IV.A. Biophysical Journal, 1956-2008; 34 folders (2.5 linear feet)
    Correspondence, financial reports, agendas, and transition plan material relating to the Biophysical Journal arranged in alphabetical order by topic.
    - Agendas/Reports, 1990-1991 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Brochures (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Brochures, Career in Biophysics, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - Budget, Projections, 1991-1997 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - CADMUS, 1993-98 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, 1956-1959 (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence, 1960-1973 (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence, 1986-1991 (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence, Jan-June 1992 (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, July-Dec 1992 (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence, 1993-96 (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence, Editorial Board, 1964-1971 (Box 20, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence, Editorial Board, 1972-1973 (Box 20, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence, Editorial Board, 1990-1996 (Box 20, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence, Editor Search, 1990-1992 (Box 20, Folder 29)
    - Correspondence, Gift Subscriptions, 1991-1996 (Box 20, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence, Journal Changes, 1992 (Box 20, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence, Protein Science, 1992-1993 (Box 20, Folder 32)
    - Correspondence, Rockefeller University Press, 1989-1995 (Box 20, Folder 33)
    - Financial Reports, Rockefeller University Press, 1988-6/1991 (Box 20, Folder 34)
    - Financial Reports, Rockefeller University Press, 7/1991-1994 (Box 20, Folder 35)
    - Financial Reports, Statistics, 1969-1996 (Box 20, Folder 36)
    - Meeting Materials, Editorial Board, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 37)
    - Miscellaneous Meetings, 1989-1996 (Box 20, Folder 38)
    - Notices, 1960-67 (Box 20, Folder 39)
    - Proposal, 1959 (Box 20, Folder 40)
    - Reports, Internet Progress, 1996 (Box 20, Folder 41)
    - Rosters, Editorial Boards, 1960-73 (Box 20, Folder 42)
    - Science & Technology Advisory Information System, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 43)
    - Transition Plan, Correspondence, 1992-94 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Transition Plan, Ad Hoc Committee, 1989-91 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Transition Plan, Conway Group, 1992-94 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Transition Plan, Journal Changes, 1992-94 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Transition Plan, Manuscript Processing Manager, 1993-94 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - January 1976-October 1976 (Box 23)
    - November 1976-June 1977 (Box 24)
    - July 1977-March 1978 (Box 25)
    - April 1978-October 1978 (Box 26)
    - November 1978-April 1980 (Box 27)
    - May 1980-Septmber 1980 (Box 28)
    - September 1980-October 1980 (Box 29)
    - November 1980-February 1980 (Box 30)
    - February 1981-June 1981 (Box 31)
    - June 1981-August 1981 (Box 32)
    - September 1981-November 1981 (Box 33)
    - December 1981-January 1982 (Box 34)
    - February 1982-May 1982 (Box 35)
    - June 1982-June 1983 (Box 36)
    - July 1983-February 1984 (Box 37)
    - February 1984-September 1984 (Box 38)
    - October 1984-May 1985 (Box 39)
    - June 1985-February 1986 (Box 40)
    - February 1986-September 1986 (Box 41)
    - October 1986-March 1987 (Box 42)
    - April 1987-December 1987 (Box 43)
    - February 1988-February 1990 (Box 44)
    - July 1990-December 1990 (Box 45)
    - January 1991-May 1991 (Box 46)
    - June 1991-November 1991 (Box 47)
    - December 1991-March 1992 (Box 48)
    - April 1992-August 1992 (Box 49)
    - September 1992-February 1993 (Box 50)
    - March 1993-August 1993 (Box 51)
    - September 1993-February 1994 (Box 52)
    - February 1994-June 1994 (Box 53)
    - July 1996-November 1996 (Box 54)
    - December 1996-March 1997 (Box 55)
    - April 1997-September 1997 (Box 56)
    - October 1997-February 1998 (Box 57)
    - February 1998-July 1998 (Box 58)
    - August 1998-Janurary 1999 (Box 59)
    - January 1999-June 1999 (Box 60)
    - July 1999-December 1999 (Box 61)
    - January 2000-May 2000 (Box 62)
    - June 2000-July 2000 (Box 63)
    - September 2000-February 2001 (Box 64)
    - March 2001-August 2001 (Box 65)
    - September 2001-February 2002 (Box 66)
    - March 2002-July 2002 (Box 67)
    - July 2002-October 2002 (Box 68)
    - October 2002-January 2003 (Box 69)
    - January 2003-February 2003 (Box 70)
    - February 2003-March 2003 (Box 71)
    - April 2003-May 2003 (Box 72)
    - May 2003-July 2003 (Box 73)
    - April 2003-May 2003 (Box 74)
    - May 2003-July 2003 (Box 75)
    - August 2003-September 2003 (Box 76)
    - October 2003-November 2003 (Box 77)
    - October 2003-January 2004 (Box 78)
    - January 2004-February 2004 (Box 79)
    - February 2004-May 2004 (Box 80)
    - May 2004-July 2004 (Box 81)
    - July 2004-September 2004 (Box 82)
    - September 2004-November 2004 (Box 83)
    - November 2004-January 2005 (Box 84)
    - January 2005-January 2005 (Box 85)
    - January 2005-February 2005 (Box 86)
    - February 2005-March 2005 (Box 87)
    - March 2005-April 2005 (Box 88)
    - May 2005-June 2005 (Box 89)
    - June 2005-July 2005 (Box 90)
    - July 2005-August 2005 (Box 91)
    - September 2005-October 2005 (Box 92)
    - October 2005-November 2005 (Box 93)
    - November 2005-October 2005 (Box 94)
    - January 2006-January 2006 (Abstracts) (Box 95)
    - January 2006-February 2006 (Box 96)
    - February 2006-March 2006 (Box 97)
    - March 2006-April 2006 (Box 98)
    - April 2006-May 2006 (Box 99)
    - May 2006- July 2006 (Box 100)
    - July 2006-September 2006 (Box 101)
    - September 2006-November 2006 (Box 102)
    - November 2006-December 2006 (Box 103)
    - January 2007-March 2007 (Box 104)
    - March 2007-June 2007 (Box 105)
    - July 2007-October 2007 (Box 106)
    - November 2007-January 2008 (Box 107)
    - January 2008-March 2008 (Box 108)
    - May 2008-August 2008 (Box 109)
    - August 2008-November 2008 (Box 110)
    - Abstracts 1960, 1961, 1962, 1963, 1964 (Box 111)
    - Abstracts 1965-1970 (Box 112)
    - Abstracts 1971-1973, 1975-1976, 1978 (Box 113)
    - Membership List and Directory 1959-1989/1990 (Box 114)
    - Membership List and Directory 1990/1991-2000 (Box 115)
    - Programs 1983, 1994, 2001 (Box 116)
  - Subseries IV.B. Newsletter, 1958-2003; bulk 1970-1997; 8 folders (.5 linear feet)
    Printed copies of the Biophysical Society newsletter with pertinent correspondence and reports arranged in order by date.
    - Correspondence, Reports, 1965 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, Reports, 1966 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1990-96 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Copies, 1958-67, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Copies, 1970-1979 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Copies, 1980-1989 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Copies, 1990, 1992-97, 1999-2003 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Copies, Spectrum, 1988-89, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - May 2007-April 2008 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Subseries IV.C. Publications Committee, 1956-1996; bulk 1988-1993; 13 folders (.5 linear feet)
    Correspondence, agendas, reports, and proceedings of said committee arranged in alphabetical order.
    - Correspondence, 1957-1960 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, 1961-1965 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, 1989-1993 (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, 1993-1996 (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, R. Gunn, 1992-1993 (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - Meeting Agendas, 1988-1990 (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Meetings, 1989-1992 (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - Proceedings & Publications, 1956-59 (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - Reports, 1989 (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - Reports, Minutes, 1989-1991 (Box 21, Folder 25)
    - Reports, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 26)
    - Reports, 1990-1993 (Box 21, Folder 27)
- Series V. Affiliated Societies, 1964-2007; bulk 1989-2002; 28 folders (1.75 linear feet)
  Correspondence, meeting files, and reports from societies connected to the Biophysical Society arranged into three Subseries in alphabetical order.
  - Subseries V.A. Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology (FASEB, 1988-2002; 24 folders (1.25 linear feet)
    Correspondence, reports, and meeting files arranged in alphabetical order.
    - Annual Report, 1992, 1995-96 (Box 21, Folder 28)
    - Board Meeting, 1991 (Box 21, Folder 29)
    - Board Meeting, March 1993 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Board Meeting, 1991 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Board Meeting, March 1993 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Board Meeting, Sept 1993 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Board of Directors Meeting, Dec 1999 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Board of Directors Meeting, May 9, 2000 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Board of Directors Meeting, Sept 2000 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Board of Directors Meeting, May 8, 2001 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Board of Directors, May 7, 2002 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, Editor Search, Jan. 17, 1995-Aug. 9, 1995 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, May 29, 1998-July 25, 2001 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Editor-in-Chief Search Committee, 1994-95, misc. (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Editor-in-Chief Search Committee, Candidates & their C.V.'s (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Editor-in-Chief Search Committee, Info packet for Teleconference, Jan. 11, 1995 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous, 1989-92 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1988-96 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Society Presidents, Nov. 1996 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Summer Research Conferences, 1999 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Summer Research Conferences, 2000 (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - Summer Research Conference, 2001 (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - Summer Research Conference, Feb 2002 (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - Summer Research Conference, July 2002 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Subseries V.B. International Union of Pure and Applied Biophysics (IUPAB), 1964-1996; bulk 1990-1996; 4 folders (.25 linear feet)
    Correspondence and miscellaneous files arranged in alphabetical order.
    - General Assembly, August 1996 (Box 22, Folder 23)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1964-67, 1990-93 (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - National Research Council, 1996 (Box 22, Folder 25)
    - Survey of Graduate Education in Biophysics in the United States (Box 22, Folder 26)
  - Subseries V.C. Bridging the Sciences Coalition, 2002-2007; 5 folders (.25 linear feet)
    Correspondence, reports, and meeting files arranged in chronological order.
    - Bridging the Sciences Coalition Planning (Box 22, Folder 27)
    - 2005 Meeting Reports (Box 22, Folder 28)
    - June 2006 Meeting Reports (Box 22, Folder 29)
    - July 2007 Meeting Reports (Box 22, Folder 30)
    - U.S. Genomics (Box 22, Folder 31)